Guide to the United States Power Squadrons District 16 records 1939-2020
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
United States Power Squadrons District 16 records
1939-2020
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0250USPowerSquadron
United States Power Squadrons--District 16
26.5 linear ft.
The United States Power Squadrons (USPS) comprise a non-profit boating organization dedicated to promoting education about boating safety to make the experience of boating more enjoyable. District 16 of the USPS was founded in 1944 and includes the majority of boating areas in Washington State. The Bellingham Power Squadron is located in District 16. The USPS District 16 records are comprised of financial documents, membership information, annual reports, photo albums, books, magazines, posters, plaques, yacht club yearbooks, ephemera, and electronic files.
The United States Power Squadrons (USPS) comprise a non-profit boating organization dedicated to promoting education about boating safety to make the experience of boating more enjoyable. USPS activities include teaching boating, seamanship, and engine maintenance courses, and conducting district meetings, educational seminars, and seasonal conferences.
The USPS is made up of thirty-three districts containing a total of four hundred and fifty squadrons across the United States. District 16 of the USPS was founded in 1944, and includes seventeen squadrons representing the majority of boating areas in Washington State. The Bellingham Power Squadron is located in District 16.
References:
Hearsey, Herbert R. District 16 United States Power Squadron: Fifty Years of Growth 1944-1994 50th Anniversary. Bellingham, WA: Western Washington University Printing and Publishing Services, 1995.
The United States Power Squadrons website, accessed February 1, 2010, http://www.usps.org/newpublic2/about.html.
The United States Power Squadrons District 16 website, accessed February 1, 2010, http://www.usps.org/d16/.
The United States Power Squadrons District 16 records date between 1939 and 2020. The records reflect the organizational activities of the District 16 (regional), Bellingham (local), and Agate Pass Power Squadrons. They are comprised of minutes, office and committee files, treasurer’s files, bylaws, correspondence, handbooks/manuals, squadron histories, information on conferences and councils, publications and newsletters, awards and memorabilia, and photographs.
The United States Power Squadrons District 16 records are organized in accordance with the following series arrangement:
Series I. Minutes, 1946-2009
Series II. Office and Committee Files, 1946-2003
Series III. Bylaws, 1947-2006
Series IV. Correspondence, 1988-1995
Series V. Squadron Histories, 1956-2003
Series VI. Conferences/Councils, 1964-2008
Series VII. Manuals and Handbooks, 1941-2001
Series VIII. Publications and Newsletters, 1958-2012
Series IX. Membership Information, 1941-2009
Series X. Bellingham Power Squadron Files, 1958-2017
Series XI. Agate Pass Records, 1953-2020
Series XII. Photographs, 1945-1994
Series XIII. Awards and Memorabilia, 1946-1990
Series XIV. Oversized Materials, 1939-1970
The collection is open to the public.
Herbert R. Hearsey donated an initial group of United States Power Squadrons District 16 records to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies in 1998.
Additional donations made by Ann Waltner in September 2006 and March 2008.
Agate Pass Records donated by Dave McBride in October 2020.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
United States Power Squadrons--District 16--Archives; Bellingham Power Squadron (Bellingham, Wash.)--Archives; Bellingham Power Squadron (Bellingham, Wash.)
Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources
Boats and boating--Washington (State)--History--Sources; Boats and boating--Washington (State)--Photographs; Motorboats--Societies, etc.--Washington (State)--History--Sources; Motorboats--Societies, etc.--Washington (State)--Photographs
Sports and Recreation
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Minutes, 1946-2009; Series I.
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (Bound Volume #1), 1946-1974 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (Bound Volume #2), 1975-1983 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (Bound Volume #3), 1983-1988 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (Bound Volume #4), Fall Council 1988 to Spring Conference, 1991 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (3-Ring Binder), 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (3-Ring Binder), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes (3-Ring Binder), 1995-1997 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes Copy of First Minutes Extant Annual Conference, 1945 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes, 1982 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - USPS District 16 Minutes, 2003 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - USPS District 16 Index to Minutes for Volumes 1-3, 1946-1988 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Minutes, 1958-1980 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Minutes, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron Minutes, 2006-2009 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Office and Committee Files, 1946-2003; Series II.
  Some of the files appear to be from the treasurer’s files.
  - Change of Watch, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Executive Department, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Educational Department, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Administrative Department, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Secretary’s Department, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - District 16 Bylaws, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Governing Boards and Annual Meeting Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Operating Committee Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Treasurer’s Department, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Planning Committee, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Awards, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Public Relations, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Secretary’s Department, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Cooperative Charting, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Educational Fund, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - National Safety Bulletins, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Education Seminar, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Spring Council, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Officer’s Directory, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Spring Conference, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Legislative, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Governing Board Nominations, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Voyage of the Ensign, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Operations Training, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - Change of Watch, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 3/26)
  - District Meeting Tally Sheets, 1991 (Box-folder 3/27)
  - Blank Resume Forms, Undated (Box-folder 3/28)
  - National Officers Directory, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 3/29)
  - Blank Squadron Status Forms, Undated (Box-folder 3/30)
  - Membership Committee, 2002 (Box-folder 3/31)
  - Executive Notebook, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Executive Notebook Continued, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Executive Book, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Education, 1989 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Education, 1990 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - National Cruise Nor’westing, 1988 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - District 32, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Resumes, 1987 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - State of Washington National Safe Boating Week Proclamation, 1991 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - State of Washington National Safe Boating Week Proclamation, 1992 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Radio Technology, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Safety, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Legislation, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Public Relations, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Cooperative Charting, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - CPS Liaison, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Boat Show, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - District 16 Liaison, 1986 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Spring Conference Orientation for New Commanders, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Merit Marks, 1987 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - District Commander’s (D/C’s) Report on Squadrons, 1987 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - National Cruise, 1988 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Portugal Study Tour, 1987 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - Governing Board Minutes, 1987 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Governing Board Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Operating Committee Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4/26)
  - District 16 Legislative Reports, 1986 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - District 16 PRO Reports, 1986 (Box-folder 4/28)
  - National Liaison Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Executive Department, 1986 (Box-folder 4/30)
  - DEO Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/31)
  - Administrative Department, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/32)
  - Secretary, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/33)
  - Treasurer, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/34)
  - Governing Board (GB) Minutes, 1986 (Box-folder 4/35)
  - CPS Liaison, 1986 (Box-folder 4/36)
  - D-16 Co-Op Charting, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/37)
  - CPS Meetings, 1986 (Box-folder 4/38)
  - District Commander (D/C) District Internal Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/39)
  - Fall Conference, 1986 (Box-folder 4/40)
  - District Commander (D/C) External Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/41)
  - District Commander’s (D/C’s) Report on Squadrons, 1985 (Box-folder 4/42)
  - Items from Closed District Commander’s (D/C’s) Meetings, 1985 (Box-folder 4/43)
  - Membership, 1985 (Box-folder 4/44)
  - District 16, Planning Committee Reports, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4/45)
  - USPS Expenses, 1985 (Box-folder 4/46)
  - Operating Committee (OP/COM) Minutes, 1986 (Box-folder 4/47)
  - Safety Bulletins, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 4/48)
  - Public Relations (PR), 1982 (Box-folder 4/49)
  - PR Bulletins, 1981 (Box-folder 4/50)
  - Change of Watch Information, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 4/51)
  - Educational Department Notices, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4/52)
  - Minutes of National Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4/53)
  - Legislative, 1981 (Box-folder 4/54)
  - General Safety Bulletins, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 4/55)
  - Operations Training Newsletter, 1981 (Box-folder 4/56)
  - Radio Technical Bulletins, 1981 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - D/16 Newsletters, 1984 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - D/16, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - National Bridge Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - National Directory Forms, 1986 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Educational Department, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Governing Board and Operating Committee Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - U.S. Coast Guard VHS “Making It Happen”, Undated (Box-folder 5/9)
  - D/16 Membership Records, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Cruising Guide Handbook, 1984 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - District 16 Membership, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - District 16 Awards, 1987 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - National Directory Forms for D/16, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - District Commander’s Newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - District Commander’s Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - District Commander’s External Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Executive Department, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Teaching Aids Catalog, 1987 (Box-folder 5/19)
  - Educational Department, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/20)
  - Administrative Department, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Secretary’s Department, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Treasurer’s Department, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/23)
  - District 16 Bylaws, 1987 (Box-folder 5/24)
  - District 16 Planning Committee, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/25)
  - Operations Training, 1987 (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Coop Charting, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Educational Fund, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 5/28)
  - State Boating Safety, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 5/29)
  - Educational Department, 1987 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - Washington State Boating Safety Study, 1987 (Box-folder 5/31)
  - Boaters Task Force Meeting, 1987 (Box-folder 5/32)
  - NASBLA and National Boating Federation, 1987 (Box-folder 5/33)
  - Spring Council, 1989 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - Educational Seminars, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 5/35)
  - District 16 Fall Council, 1987 (Box-folder 5/36)
  - District 16 Fall Conference, 1987 (Box-folder 5/37)
  - District 16 Rendezvous, 1987 (Box-folder 5/38)
  - District 16 Legislative Reports, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/39)
  - National Safety Bulletins, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/40)
  - National Liaison Mailings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/41)
  - Public Relations Mailings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5/42)
  - CPS (Canadian Power Squadron) Pacific Mainland District, 1987 (Box-folder 5/43)
  - CPS (Canadian Power Squadron) Vancouver Island District, 1987 (Box-folder 5/44)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins and Rosters, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Merit Marks, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Boating Class-Public, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Budget, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Pennants, Undated (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1946 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Financial Records, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Membership Records, 1954 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Membership Records, 1955 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Educational Department, 1956 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Financial Records, 1957 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box-folder 6/27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box-folder 6/28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box-folder 6/29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box-folder 6/30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box-folder 6/31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box-folder 6/32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box-folder 6/33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box-folder 6/34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box-folder 6/35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box-folder 6/36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box-folder 6/37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box-folder 6/38)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box-folder 6/39)
  - Income and Disbursements, 1968 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Treasurer’s Files, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Treasurer’s Files, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - For Income Return, 1969 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - General Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Receipts and Disbursement Journals, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - District 16 Dues Notices, 1971 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - IRS Documents, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Income Tax, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Accounts Payable, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Financial Reports, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - District 16 Billing, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Bank Statements, Cancelled Checks, Deposit Slips, Deposit Envelopes, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Treasurer’s Files, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Check Register, 1966 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Budgets and Treasurer’s Reports (3 Ring Binder), 1967-1972 (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Bills Paid, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Spring Conference Records, 1973 (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Cardinal Points and Advertising, 1973 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Ledger, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Assessments, 1973 (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Ledger Summaries, 1972 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 7/26)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 7/28)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1976-1977 (Box-folder 7/29)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 7/30)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 7/31)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7/32)
  - Canadian Power Squadron Pacific Mainland, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Canadian Power Squadron Vancouver Island, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - United States Coast Guard Auxiliary, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - District 16 Insurance, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (Bound Volume), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Financial Ledger, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Assessments, 1992 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Treasurer’s Report, 2003 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - District 16 Treasurer’s Files (3 Ring Binder), 1984-1986 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Handouts and Notices, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - District 16 Committee Nominations, 2002 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - District 16 Rendezvous Schedule, 2002 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - District 16 EDM III Boat Handling Committee, 2002 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - District 16 New ED Department Structure and Leadership Schedule, 2002 (Box-folder 8/17)
- Bylaws, 1947-2006; Series III.
  - Revised Bylaws, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1959, 1976, 1978 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Bylaws, 1947-1991 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - District 16 Proposed Bylaws, 2002 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - District 16 Bylaws Article 7 and 8, 2002 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Bellingham Sail and Power Squadron, Bylaws, Revised Edition, 1999 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Bellingham Sail and Power Squadron, Bylaws, Revised Edition, 2008 (Box-folder 9/7)
- Correspondence, 1988-1995; Series IV.
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 9/14)
- Squadron Histories, 1956-2003; Series V.
  - District 16 Squadron History (1939-Present), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Agate Pass Squadron History, 1956-1995 (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Bellevue Squadron History, 1958-1998 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Bellingham Squadron History, 1959-2003 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Bremerton Squadron History, 1952-1997 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Deception Pass Squadron History, 1976-1998 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Everett Squadron History, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 9/21)
  - Friday Harbor Squadron History, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Olympia Squadron History, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - North Olympic Squadron History, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Pole Pass Squadron History, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Portland Squadron History, 1942-1992 (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Port Townsend Squadron History (Defunct 1985), 1976-1985 (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Possession Sound Squadron History, 1961-1997 (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Poverty Bay Squadron History, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Seattle Squadron History, 1945-1998 (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Spokane Squadron History, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 9/31)
  - Tacoma Squadron History, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 9/32)
  - Canadian Squadron History, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 9/33)
  - District 16 Genealogy Chart, Undated (Box-folder 9/34)
  - District 16 Genealogy Chart, Undated (Box-folder 9/35)
- Conferences/Councils, 1964-2008; Series VI.
  - Spring Seminar for District Commanders and Educational Offices, New York, 1964 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Conferences, 1981 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Conferences, 1984 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Conferences, 1985 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Conferences, 1986 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Conferences, 1987 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Conferences, 1988 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Conferences, 1989 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Conferences, 1990 (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Conferences, 1991 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Conferences, 1992 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Conferences, 1993 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Conferences, 1994 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Conferences, 1995 (Box-folder 10/14)
  - Conferences, 1996 (Box-folder 10/15)
  - Conferences, 1997 (Box-folder 10/16)
  - Minutes, Handouts & Conferences, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 10/17)
  - Conferences, 1998 (Box-folder 10/18)
  - Spring Council Meeting, 2000 (Box-folder 10/19)
  - Minutes, Handouts & Conferences, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 10/20)
  - Conferences, Councils, & Seminars, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 10/21)
  - Spring Conference Photographs, 2000 (Box-folder 10/22)
  - Spring Conference Photographs, 2001 (Box-folder 10/23)
  - Conference and Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Box-folder 10/24)
  - Spring Conference, Draft Agenda, 2002 (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Fall Conference, 2002 (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Conferences, Reports, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 10/27)
  - Fall Council, 2003 (Box-folder 10/28)
  - Conferences, Councils, and Rendezvous, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 10/29)
  - Conferences, 2008 (Box-folder 10/30)
  - Council and Rendezvous Information, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 10/31)
  - Fall Council, Spring Conference, 2009 (Box-folder 10/32)
- Manuals and Handbooks, 1941-2001; Series VII.
  - Meetings Guidelines, 1991 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Job Descriptions and Schedule of Operations, 1988 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Handbook and Roster, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Officer’s Manual, 1965 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Officer’s Manual, 1978 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Operations Manual, 1984 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Public Relations Officer’s Manual, 1955 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - Editor’s Handbook, 1979 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - “Rules of the Road”, Committee for Advanced Grades, 1979 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Keeping Our Waters Safe and Secure Pamphlet, Undated (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Geodetic Mark Recovery (Field Guide and Summary), 2001 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - Boat Smart: Keeping Your Crew Safe and Well, 1997 (Box-folder 11/12)
- Publications and Newsletters, 1958-2012; Series VIII.
  The Publications include newsletters of the Bellingham Power Squadron, USPS District 16, and the United States Power Squadron National Newsletter.
  - District 16 Nor’ Westing Cruising Guide, 1988 (Box-folder 11/13)
  - 10 Year Membership Survey Analysis, 1981 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Fifty Years of Growth (1944-1994), 1995 (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Hinden Case, 1981 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Web Posts USPS Joins w/Yacht Club Leaders, 2007 (Box-folder 11/17)
  - Article “U.S. Power Squadrons: 66 Years of Service” By: Phyllis and Bill Bultmann, 1980 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - National Safe Boating Week, 1990 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron The Next Decade (1983/84 to 1992/1993) (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Bellingham Power Squadron The First Twenty-Five Years, 1997 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - Bell Signals (Bellingham Power Squadron Newsletter), August 1970-May 1979 (Box-folder 11/22)
  - Bell Signals, September 1979-May 1983 (Box-folder 11/23)
  - Bell Signals, September 1983-May1986 (Book says 1985 Really 1986) (Box-folder 11/24)
  - Bell Signals, June 1986-April 1990 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Bell Signals, May 1990-August 1993 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Bell Signals, October 1993-December 1996 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Bell Signals, 1997 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Bell Signals, 1998 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Bell Signals, January 1999-February 2000 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Bell Signals, March 2000-October 2001 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Bell Signals, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Bell Signals, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Bell Signals, April 2007-March 2009 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Bell Signals, 2008 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Bell Signals, 2009 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Bell Signals, 2010 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Bell Signals, 2011 (Box-folder 12/14)